troteclaser.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy and Data Protection on www.troteclaser.com

Request a demo

### 1\. General information

Dealing sensitively with customer data is of greatest importance for Trotec Laser GmbH (“Trotec”, “we”, “us”). Thus, personal data is collected, stored and used in accordance with the data protection regulations, particularly the Austrian Data Protection Act in its current version ("DSG") and the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") for fulfilling contractual obligations. Any use over and above this, which is not justified on the basis of overriding legitimate interests in accordance with the applicable Data Protection Act, is permissible only after your consent following prior informatoin. You can revoke your consent at any time (e.g. via an e-mail to [trotec@troteclaser.com](mailto:trotec@troteclaser.com) ). This does, however, not affect the right to data processing for the performance of a contract. More details about the information that we collect, process and use when you visit and use our website [www.troteclaser.com](http://www.troteclaser.com/) ("website") have been provided below. 

### Managing Your Information Preferences

You can review, correct, update, or change your personal data or opt out of receiving certain e-mails by e-mailing us at [trotec@troteclaser.com](mailto:trotec@troteclaser.com) . You are able to opt out of receiving marketing e-mails from us. If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please e-mail us at the same address.

### 2\. Which of your data does Trotec process?

**Contact and enquiry data:** When you actively establish contact with us (e.g. via e-mail or via our contact form), the data and details (name, address, company name, question, telephone number, e-mail and content of the enquiry) are processed. 

**Registration data:** If you register for seminars and workshops, we record the registration data provided (name, company name, address, e-mail, telephone, booked events). 

**Location data:** If you are searching for a Trotec location near you, we process the location (address) specified by you for displaying the hits. We delete this information after your visit to the website. 

**Technical data:** We record the IP address of your device, the Internet browser used and your OS, your clicking behaviour on the website and the website from which you visit us. This personal data can also be collected by using cookies (see below).

### 3\. For which purposes does Trotec process your personal data?

Trotec collects, stores and uses your personal data (i) to allow you to access special information, (ii) to contact you within the scope of the business relationship (iii) to improve the services provided by Trotec and the website in accordance with Art 6 Para 1 lit b GDPR. 

**Insofar as it is necessary for contract fulfilment, your personal data will be disclosed to companies of the Trodat Trotec Group or their sales and service partners** in the countries relevant to you so that they can take action on behalf of Trotec Laser GmbH. We will therefore send your data to third parties only for the fulfilment of our obligations.

### 4\. How long does Trotec store your personal data?

Your personal data will be stored by us for as long as required to fulfil our obligations towards users. However, due to our retention obligations, we usually store your personal data in relation to orders and bookings for three or a maximum of seven years after contract fulfilment. 

### 5\. Cookies and Google Analytics

Like most websites, we use cookies. Cookies are small text files which a website or your service provider places on the hard disk of your device via the web browser so that the website can be more conveniently designed and your user behaviour on the website can be understood better. 

Trotec mainly uses (i) functional cookies, which are necessary for operating our website, and (ii) cookies, which collect statistical data about the use of the website, so that we can improve our services. Trotec occasionally also uses trustworthy cookies from third-party providers who collect this information for us. 

This website also uses **Google Analytics** , a web analysis service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Trotec uses data from Google Analytics to improve the website for the visitors. This data shortens the loading times and makes the content that is are generated more interesting for the visitors. 

The following information is collected by Google Analytics: browser, device type, device model, location, country, city, service provider, monitor resolution, dwell time, language, operating system, visited pages on the website. The IP addresses are anonymised in advance and a personal reference cannot be established with the collection of data. 

The information created by the Google Analytics cookie concerning your use of this website is generally transmitted to Google’s servers outside Europe (e.g. in the USA) and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to produce reports concerning the website activities for the website operator and to produce additional services associated with the use of Internet and the website. Google may also transfer this information to third parties, if this is legally permitted or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google. For more information about how to opt out of having your information used by Google Analytics, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>. 

You can prevent the cookies from being installed by means of a relevant setting in your browser software; however, we must point out that in such a case, all functions of this website will not be available to you in their full capacity. Unless you opt out, the cookies are stored on your end device for a duration of 26 months.

### 6\. Online Tracking

Our systems do not recognize browser “Do Not Track” signals, but several of our service providers who utilize these cookies on our website enable you to opt out of targeted advertising practices. To learn more about these advertising practices or to opt out of this type of advertising, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).  We also provide you with additional tools to opt out of marketing from us.  You can learn about this in the “Managing Your Information Preferences” section of this Privacy Policy.

### 7\. Social plugins

Our website uses the following social plugins (“plugins”) of various social networks. For interaction with social plugins, the social networks exclusively process personal data as follows, if necessary:

  * **Use of Facebook plugins**

Plugins from the social network, Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA are integrated into our website. You can identify the Facebook plugins by the Facebook logo (white “f” on a blue tile) on our website. You can find an overview of the Facebook plugins here: <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins>. 

If you visit our website, a direct link will be established between your browser and the Facebook server by the plugin. With this, Facebook will receive information that you have visited our website with your IP address. If you click on the Facebook “Like” button while you are logged into your Facebook account, you can link the contents of our website to your Facebook profile. This way, Facebook can allocate your visit to our website to your user account. We would like to point out here that we do not receive any information about the content of the data sent or its use by Facebook. Additional information regarding this can be found in the data protection policy of Facebook at [http://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php ](http://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php)

  * **Use of Twitter plugins**

Our website uses plugins of the Twitter microblogging service, which is operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA ("Twitter"). The plugins are marked with a Twitter logo, e.g. in the form of a blue “Twitter bird”. You can find an overview of the Twitter plugins and their appearance here: [https://dev.twitter.com/web/tweet-button. ](https://dev.twitter.com/web/tweet-button.)

If you access our website, which contains such a plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection to the Twitter servers. The content of the plugin is sent by Twitter directly to your browser and integrated into the website. Through this integration, Twitter receives information that your browser has accessed the respective page of our website even if you do not have a profile at Twitter or are not currently logged into Twitter. This information (including your IP address) is sent by your browser directly to a Twitter server in the USA and stored there. If you are logged into Twitter, Twitter can associate your visit to our website directly with your Twitter account. If you interact with the plugins, e.g. click on the “Tweet” button, the corresponding information is also sent directly to a Twitter server and stored there. The information is also published on your Twitter account and your contacts are displayed there. 

For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and further processing and use of the data by Twitter, as well as your relevant rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy, please refer to the data protection policy of Twitter: <https://twitter.com/de/privacy>

If you do not want Twitter to allocate the data collected through our website directly to your Twitter account, you must log out of our website prior to your visit. You can also completely prevent the loading of the Twitter plugins for your browser, e.g. with the script blocker "NoScript" ( <http://noscript.net/> ).

  * **Use of Google+ plugins**

Our website uses so-called social plugins (“plugins”) of the Google+ social network, which is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). The plugins are e.g. identifiable by buttons with the “G+” symbol on a white or coloured background. You can find an overview of the Google plugins and their appearance here: <https://developers.google.com/+/web/>. 

If you access a page on our website, which contains such a plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection to the Google servers. The content of the plugin is sent by Google directly to your browser and is integrated into the website. Through the integration, Google receives information that your browser has accessed the respective page of our website, even if you do not have a profile at Google+ or are not currently logged into Google+. This information (including your IP address) is sent by your browser directly to a Google server in the USA and stored there. 

If you are logged into Google+, Google can associate your visit to our website directly with your Google+ account. If you interact with the plugins, e.g., click on the “G+” button, the corresponding information is also sent directly to a Google server and stored there. The information is also published on Google+ and your contacts are displayed there. 

For the purpose and scope of data collection, further processing and use of the data by Google, as well as your relevant rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy, please refer to the data protection policy of Google: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

If you do not want Google to allocate the data collected through our website directly to your profile on Google+, you must log out of our Google+ website prior to your visit. You can also completely prevent the loading of the Google plugins for your browser, e.g. with the script blocker "NoScript" ( <http://noscript.net/> ).

  * **Use of YouTube plugins**

We also have YouTube videos and plugins integrated on our website. 

If you play a video or click on the button, YouTube cookies are stored on our computer and the following data is transferred to Google, Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, as the YouTube operator: IP address and cookie ID, the specific address of the page, which is accessed on our website, language setting of the browser, system date and time of the access and the identifier of your browser. The data is transmitted, regardless of whether you are registered and logged in at Google. If you are logged in, these data is allocated directly to your account. 

If you do not want the allocation to your profile, you must log out before activating the button. YouTube or Google, Inc. stores this data as user profiles and uses it for advertising purposes, market research and/or needs-based design of its websites. Such an evaluation is particularly done (even for users who are not logged in) to provide need-based advertising and to inform other users about your activities on our website. You are entitled to a right to object the formation of these user profiles, whereby you must contact Google Inc., as the operator of YouTube, in order to exercise this. You can obtain additional information about the purpose and scope of the data collection and its processing by Google, Inc. at <http://www.google.at/intl/de/policies/privacy/> . We do not process the personal data, which we collect.

  * **Use of Instagram plugins**

We use plugins of the Instagram social network, which is operated by Instagram LLC., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, on our website. The plugins are marked with an Instagram logo, e.g. in the form of an “Instagram camera”. You can find an overview of the Instagram plugins and their appearance here: <http://blog.instagram.com/post/36222022872/introducing-instagram-badges> . 

If you access our website, your browser establishes a direct connection to the Instagram servers. The content of the plugin is sent by Instagram directly to your browser and integrated into the website. Through this integration, Instagram receives the information that your browser has accessed the respective page of our website, even if you do not have an Instagram profile or are not currently logged in. This information (including your IP address) is sent by your browser directly to an Instagram server in the USA and stored there. 

If you are logged into Instagram, Instagram can associate your visit to our website directly with your Instagram account. If you interact with the plugins, for example, click on the “Instagram” button, this information is also sent directly to an Instagram server and stored there. The information is also published on your Instagram account and your contacts are displayed there. 

For the purpose and scope of data collection, the further processing and used of the data by Instagram, as well as your relevant rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy, please refer to the data protection policy of Instagram: <https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388> 

### 8\. How does Trotec protect your data?

We take appropriate technical and organisational security measures within the scope of Art. 5 Para 1 lit f or Art. 32 GDPR to protect your personal data from unintentional or unlawful deletion, modification, damage or loss as well as against unauthorised disclosure or unauthorised access. Furthermore, we and our employees undertake to comply with data secrecy.  However, no data transmission over the Internet or other network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  As a result, while we strive to protect information transmitted on or through the website, we cannot and do not guarantee the security of any information you transmit on or through the website, and you do so at your own risk.

### 9\. Links

Our website may contain links to other websites or allow others to send you such links.  A link to a third party’s website does not mean that we endorse it or that we are affiliated with it.  We do not exercise control over third-party websites.  You access such third-party websites or content at your own risk.  You should always read the privacy policy of a third-party website before providing any information to the website.

### 10\. Processing in the United States

Please be aware that your personal data and communications may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, or country including the United States. The laws in those countries may not provide the same level of data protection compared to the country in which you initially provided your personal data. However, please rest assured that we implement all the necessary and appropriate legal, organizational and technical measures to protect your personal data. Furthermore, as regards the transfer of personal information to countries outside the EU, we have entered so-called “Standard Contractual Clauses” approved by the Commission of the European Union for international transfer of personal information to controllers or processors established in third countries as the case may be.

### 11. Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law.  We may disclose personal data and any other information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties if, in our discretion, we believe it is necessary or appropriate in order to respond to legal requests (including court orders and subpoenas), to protect the safety, property, or rights of our company or of any third party, to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity, or to comply with the law.

### 12\. Which rights do you have?

You have a right to access personal data that we process (Art. 15 GDPR). In addition, you have the right of rectification of inaccurate data and erasure ( Art. 16 and 17 GDPR). Furthermore, you have a right to restriction of the processing (Art. 18 GDPR) and the right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR). Please note that we can only respect your request to erasure if no legal retention periods or other reasons are applicable. 

You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Austrian Data Protection Authority (Barichgasse 40-42, 1030 Vienna). If you need another country than Austria, please find the corresponding Data Protection Authority under <http://archiv.dsb.gv.at/site/6211/default.aspx> . If you have any questions about your rights or the data processing, you can also contact us: 

**Trotec Laser GmbH**  
Freilingerstr. 99, 4614 Marchtrenk   
Austria  
Telephone: [+43-7201-15-244](tel:+43-7201-15-244%20)  
Fax: +43 7242 239 – 7380  
E-mail: [trotec@troteclaser.com](mailto:trotec@troteclaser.com)

**Children’s Rights**

The website is intended for users who are 13 years old or older. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal data from a child under the age of 13, we will delete such information from our records. California users under the age of 18 may request the removal of their content or information publically posted on the website by e-mailing us at [trotec@troteclaser.com](mailto:trotec@troteclaser.com) . Please note that most of the user content that appears on our website is stored and controlled by third party providers; thus, complete and comprehensive removal of the content may not be possible. 

**Your California Privacy Rights**

To opt out of sharing your personal data with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please e-mail us at [trotec@troteclaser.com](mailto:trotec@troteclaser.com) and clearly state your request, including your name, mailing address, e-mail address and phone number. Please see Section 1 - Managing Your Information Preferences for additional information.

### 13\. Privacy Policy Changes

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will inform you by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the website. Those changes will go into effect on the “Revised” date shown in the revised Privacy Policy. By continuing to use the website, you are consenting to the revised Privacy Policy. 

**PLEASE PRINT A COPY OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY FOR YOU RECORDS AND PLEASE CHECK THE WEBSITE FREQUENTLY FOR ANY CHANGES.**

## The following paragraph is only applicable for users who have explicitly agreed upon processing their data for marketing purpose:

In order to continue to be fully informed, under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a of the GDPR I furthermore permit Trotec to use my data in the context of the marketing interests described below: 

**I agree that my personal data voluntarily provided may be processed by Trotec for purposes of  **

  * **contacting me and sending me marketing and product information related to goods and services from Trotec's (new) range of products (by email, SMS, telephone, fax, via social media messenger services);**
  * **satisfaction surveys concerning service and counselling;**
  * **needs analyses;**
  * **event invitations, training opportunities, vouchers and discount promotions;**
  * **reminders when I have filled the online shopping cart, but not completed the purchase process; and**
  * **contacting in the context of regional customs and traditions, such as sending Christmas or greetings cards.**

**I understand that Trotec is a member of the Trodat Trotec Group, and in this context, I additionally agree that the above personal data may be disclosed within the Group to affiliate companies of Trotec for the above purposes of marketing, so that such affiliates may contact me to the extent agreed. A complete list of affiliated companies is available on request.  In addition, Trotec may involve third parties into the process if so required, and if the same have been carefully selected and obliged to comply with the demanding data privacy standards.**

I acknowledge that Trotec will store my personal data for a maximum of seven years after the fulfilment of the contract due to retention requirements under corporate and fiscal law. If I have registered only for the marketing purposes described above and am not a customer of Trotec, my data will be stored until my consent has been revoked, but not for more than three years after my last contact with Trotec. 

I have the right to request information about my personal data stored, and to have my data corrected or deleted at any time. I may also be entitled to demand a restriction on the processing of my data, and to have the data provided by me released in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. Furthermore, I may revoke my consent to processing of personal data for the future if the processing is based on my consent. If I no longer want to receive Trotecs' newsletter or advertising e-mails, I can click on the “unsubscribe” link, which is contained in all of the e-mails sent by Trotec. In addition to this, it is also possible to revoke by calling or e-mail. 

I am entitled to lodge a complaint with Trotec or a data protection supervisory authority. The responsible data protection supervisory authority  in Austria is: Österreichische Datenschutzbehörde [Austrian Data Protection Authority], Barichgasse 40-42, 1030 Vienna, Austria, phone: [+43 1 52 152-0](tel:+43201521520), e-mail: [dsb@dsb.gv.at](mailto:dsb@dsb.gv.at) . Data protection supervisory authorities are to be found at <http://archiv.dsb.gv.at/site/6211/default.aspx> . 

### Your right to object

As a data subject, you can object to the use of your data at any time if the processing has the purpose of direct marketing. 

Insofar as we process data for legitimate interests of Trotec or a third party, you additionally have the right to object at any time if reasons arise for this from your specific situation.
